[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[SCREAMING IN PAIN]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- [ENGINE REVVING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TRUCK HORN BLARES]
[LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- Stop!
- [GUNSHOTS]
[FIREWORKS EXPLODING]
[METAL RODS CLANGING]
- [ENGINE REVVING]
- [BUS HORN HONKS]
[GLASS SHATTERING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[GUNSHOTS]
- [TRUCK HORN HONKS]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Earlier, someone knocked
on the door.
- They left this parcel outside.
- What's inside?
- A mission. It's a job for me.
- What kind of mission?
Hunting down people
who have broken the law.
- How much are we talking?
- One hundred thousand pesos.
So, why is my youngest
always in a hurry?
We're handling a huge case
in NCIA.
It's a gold smuggling case.
Oh, Ricardo, you daughter here
is after a syndicate.
When I was her age,
I had dealt
with more serious cases.
She hasn't proven anything yet.
Sure you're prepared?
Don't mess this up.
We're ready, ma'am.
Thank you for the confidence.
Let's move!
Pops. Gabo took the mission.
The real question is,
will he do it?
Give him some time.
I have strong faith that
Gabo will carry out the mission.
Why do the two of you
look like that?
It's Chinese New Year.
We're going to Chinatown.
[LAWIN] We'll check out
what Gabo will do.
- Checkmate.
- That's it.
Huh?
[CHESS PIECE CLINKS]
[PAPANG CHUCKLING SOFTLY]
[VAN DOOR SLIDING]
Boss.
[VAN DOOR SLIDES, CLOSES]
I'll feel them out first.
If I get to explain it
to them well...
I'll tell you
if you can go upstairs.
Just find a way
to interview them!
Remember, your careers
are at stake here!
Yes, boss.
Salvador. You take care of it.
And do it well!
Do it well? And if you forget
to record it again,
I might as well just forget you.
Yes, boss.
[CHUCKLES AWKWARDLY]
Come on, let's go.
Fix your equipment.
[SALVADOR] Sir. Sir!
Oh, oh? Oh?
You're Rudy's
brother-in-law, right?
Yeah.
You're the one
who interviewed Betchay, right?
- Have you released that yet?
- That's actually my problem.
W-Where's Betchay?
Oh, they went home.
They went back
to Ginintuang Lupa.
[QUIRKY MUSIC PLAYING]
[TEKLA] Gabo!
- [DOOR CREAKS]
- [KNOCKS ON DOOR]
Gabo!
- [GABO] I'm getting dressed!
- Oh, he's getting dressed.
Do they have food?
I'm starving.
You haven't eaten breakfast?
You're always hungry.
Hey, don't touch those.
[WATER TRICKLING]
- There! A can of sardines!
- [QUIRKY MUSIC CONTINUES]
Oh, there's bread!
The perfect pair!
- Perfect pair!
- Hey! Hey!
You guys are shameless.
Hey, don't touch that.
Auntie Betchay will get pissed.
Just a few bites, man.
It's just food.
I hear you, it's just food.
But I'm telling you,
you won't like her mad.
He's right.
You'll get Gabo in trouble.
I'm starving.
I haven't eaten breakfast.
Don't you feel bad for him?
- Put it in the bowl.
- Breakfast.
We've warned you.
- Dig in.
- [TEKLA] Leave me out of that.
- Gabo.
- What's up.
- What?
- Eat with us, Gabo.
- Oh, Gabo.
- [CUTLERY CLANKS]
You guys should go.
I have to pass by the hospital.
I need to check on Papa.
Oh, we'll come with you.
No need.
Let's just meet in Chinatown.
- I'll be there.
- Okay.
We'll go there now.
For sure, it'll be packed today.
It's Chinese New Year.
Perfect!
Chinese people will be
giving out red envelopes!
- Exactly
- Mm-hmm.
- Come on.
- Be careful, okay?
Be discreet so that the person
doesn't get suspicious.
Come on, let's move.
We might miss them.
- Come on.
- Okay, then.
- Hurry.
- Grab this one!
[TEKLA] Hey, don't bring food!
All you guys do is eat.
You guys are shameless.
Oh, it's Auntie Betchay.
Auntie Betchay.
- [BETCHAY] Oh.
- How's Uncle Rudy?
He's still not well.
He is in the ICU.
Have you seen Gabo?
Oh, he's at home.
What's that?
[QUIRKY MUSIC PLAYING]
Did you get food from our home?
See? I told you.
That's enough!
We've got a much bigger problem.
I only grabbed one!
We really need
to get this job done.
We can't fail, okay?
Uncle Rudy's life is at stake.
You three, don't fool around.
Don't let Mr. Chan
get away or else!
Why do you hate us three?
Take it easy!
We won't fail! Never!
- "Never"?
- Let's go.
We might miss Mr. Chan.
Your breath stinks.
I think you're hungry. Here.
- Eat up.
- [TEKLA] Leave me out of it.
I knew it!
- They even ate my sardines!
- [GLASS BOWL BREAKS]
Hey, calm down! It's just food!
"Just food"?!
That's exactly it!
It's food!
We can't afford to buy medicine!
We can't afford
to pay hospital bills!
Does that not make you frantic?!
- Oh, please--
- I am so tired!
I'm so tired because it's always
been my responsibility!
It's always been me!
You're making
the situation worse--
I'm making it worse?!
You think I'm making it worse?!
Oh really, Mameng?
My goodness!
So now I'm making it worse.
Gosh. Argh! [TAPS LOUDLY]
Whatever. If you don't--
Damn it.
Of course it won't start
right when the owner
picks it up.
This is bad.
What could be the problem?
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINE STARTS, DIES]
Oh, Badong.
- Badong.
- Oh, Elton.
Man, you know a lot
about motorcycles, right?
I've been trying to fix this,
but the engine dies.
The owner, who's a seaman,
will pick it up today.
Can you help us?
We desperately need
the money right now.
Sure, Elton.
I'll try my best.
We really need the money
to pay the bills.
Here are the tools.
[BETCHAY]
Well, Gabo? Where is it?
Where's the promise you made?
You said you were going
to find a way
to have your father
undergo surgery.
Now, where is it? Tell me!
[MAMENG] Hey!
Don't talk to Gabo like that!
[BETCHAY] And why not?
It's the truth!
I only told the truth!
You made a promise, remember?
Didn't you say
you'd do whatever it takes
to get your father
operated on?!
So, what happened?
[SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING]
I've got a job, Auntie.
What?
A job?
You have a job? Is it true?
What kind of job is it?
I have to look for someone.
After that, I'll get paid.
- [BETCHAY SCOFFING]
- It's in Chinatown.
More nonsense again, huh?
Who are you planning
to kill this time?
Tell us so we can be prepared.
That way, we won't get
a headache
worrying about
how to help you
avoid getting locked up again!
- Your father--
- Shh!
Enough!
Come on, dear.
- Don't listen to her.
- Argh!
She's crazy.
Come on, look.
I'll take care of it.
I'll look after your father.
Your job is important.
Focus on that.
It's going to be alright.
Listen, concentrate on your job.
That's what matters.
[SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
[MAMENG] But, Gabo...
Promise me one thing.
You wouldn't do
anything stupid, alright?
I promise, Auntie.
Be careful.
[SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [ENGINE STARTS]
- [ELTON] Good job, Badong!
You got it running! Awesome!
Man, you're amazing!
- Whoo!
- Nice engine, Elton.
Of course, it's brand new!
Rudy even assembled it himself!
You know what?
Help me fix this car.
We can use the payment
for Rudy's hospital bills.
[KEYS JINGLING]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
I've been working on it
for three days,
but it just won't start.
I think the distributor is
the problem.
Or maybe it's the carburetor.
- Okay, I'll check it out.
- Thanks.
Take over.
I'll check the back.
There's a problem there too.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES]
[TARP RUSTLES, FLAPPING]
[THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING]
[THRILLING MUSIC CONTINUES]
[OLI] Uh, good morning.
- Yes?
- Can I ask a question?
- Where do the Magtibays live?
- [ENGINE STARTS]
[ENGINE ROARING]
- [WOMAN] That's their house.
- Oh, that one?
Badong!
- Who snatched the motorcycle?
- No clue!
Then how will we get paid?
Let's catch him!
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
[ENGINE REVVING]
[ENGINE ROARS]
[HEAVY THUD]
- Good day!
- Anyone home?
- Anyone home? Oh.
[SALVADOR] Good day, ma'am.
You guys again?
[SALVADOR] We'd just like
to interview you again.
Our executive producer,
Boss Arnel, is here with us.
Why? Is there a problem?
Did I say something wrong?
No, it's not that.
We liked it.
Your response was great
and full of emotions but...
But what?
We failed to record
the interview.
Oh, my goodness.
Do you even know how
to do your job?
Unbelievable!
We're busy enough as it is,
and you're still bothering us?
We'd like to do a feature on how
policemen abuse their power.
Your husband was shot,
and filing charges will
help the case a lot.
We can even provide
a lawyer for you.
[WHISPERING] Here.
Give this to them.
[QUIRKY MUSIC PLAYING]
Please consider this
as our help.
We hope this will do.
[QUIRKY MUSIC CONTINUES]
This isn't enough to buy
antibiotics for Rudy.
Oh, alright.
Here. Take this, too.
Will that be enough?
Where do you want to
do the interview? Come inside.
- Over there.
- There? Okay.
- Come in.
- [OLI] Okay, thank you.
- Thank you so much.
- We're going inside.
Thank you.
The people of Ginintuang
Lupa filed
a temporary restraining order
against us.
Then file a counter
restraining order.
Call our contacts
in the judiciary
and make sure the decision
turns in our favor.
- It's as simple as that.
- Okay. I'll do that, sir.
Manny.
[UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING]
I'm a Jacinto.
I have money and power.
We won't stop until
we kick out
all those squatters
in Ginintuang Lupa.
Yes, sir.
Oli, make sure you record it
this time, okay?
Excuse me. I'll just go over
there and make some coffee.
- Okay, thank you.
- Thank you.
- [MAMENG] Excuse me.
- [SALVADOR] Thank you.
[OLI] Thanks.
Oli, make sure you
get everything.
We can't make
any more mistakes.
Yes, boss. I got this.
- Or I'll have you fired.
- It's all good now.
- [SALVADOR] Okay. Ready?
- [OLI] Okay.
Rolling. Action!
Uh, ma'am...
How have you been
holding up
after what happened
to Mister Rudy?
He's still in the hospital--
- [THUD]
- Oh!
- Ma'am.
- Sorry about that.
We could hear you.
We're recording here.
- Sorry. The lid was hot.
- Please keep it down.
- Okay, again.
- Ready?
[OLI] Okay, go.
- [ARNEL] Rolling.
- Okay, rolling.
- Three, two, one. Action.
- Okay.
Ma'am, how have you been
holding up
since your husband,
Mister Rudy, got shot?
[IN STERN VOICE]
He's still at the hospital.
He's in the ICU
and has not woken up yet.
- [QUIRKY MUSIC PLAYING]
- Wait, cut!
You sounded angry.
Remember, your husband
is in the hospital.
Let your sadness out.
We need to show emotions.
Talk to her.
Help bring out her emotions.
- Pull out her emotions.
- [SALVADOR] Look, ma'am.
If you're angry, you won't get
sympathy from the viewers.
Instead of anger,
express more of your sadness.
I already gave you money, right?
Why are you still mad?
- You get me?
- [OLI] Tug at people's hearts.
- Tug at their heartstrings.
- That's right.
- [ARNEL] You ready, ma'am?
- [OLI] Are we good?
- [ARNEL] Okay, rolling!
- Go.
Three, two, one, action!
Ma'am, how have you been
since your husband,
Mister Rudy, got shot?
[COMICAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[VOICE SHAKING] My husband
is still at the hospital.
He hasn't woken up yet.
Ah, wait. Cut! Cut! Cut!
Let's do that again.
Ma'am, your husband
is fighting for his life.
- Yeah!
- He's on the verge of death.
He's dying.
We need to feel your sorrow
and your heartache.
Put your heart into it.
Give it your all!
Salvador, motivate her.
- [SIGHS DEEPLY] Talk to her.
- Okay, okay.
[SALVADOR] Ma'am, listen.
Here's what you should do.
Just imagine your husband
is going to die tomorrow.
- [OLI] Right.
- [SALVADOR] Okay?
- You'll be a widow forever.
- What?!
[SALVADOR]
No, just imagine it!
And you don't have any money.
- [ARNEL] Yes, perfect.
- We really don't have money.
Yeah, but just think about it,
so you can bring out
the right emotions.
- That's it. Be natural.
- [OLI] That's good.
[ARNEL] If you can cry, do it.
From 1 to 10, give us 10.
Yes, that's perfect.
Give us a bigger frown.
- Roll camera!
- Looks like she's ready!
- Ready?
- Three, two, one, action!
- Ma'am...
- [SOBBING SOFTLY]
How have you been holding up
since your husband,
Mister Rudy, got hurt?
[WAILS]
We need your help!
We don't have any money!
My husband's still confined!
He hasn't even woken up yet!
- [SALVADOR] Good. Keep it up.
- [SOBS]
We can't afford
his hospital bills!
[SOBS LOUDLY] We don't know
what else to do!
[BETCHAY CONTINUES TO WAIL]
- [WAILS LOUDER]
- [WHISPERING] Get closer.
Close up on her face.
Rudy!
- [MAMENG WAILS]
- Camera, film her!
- My brother!
- Don't miss it!
Focus on her! Come on!
- Go film Mameng!
- Take me with you, Rudy!
- [CRYING]
- What are you saying, ma'am?
Hey!
- Take you where?
- Don't leave me! [CRIES LOUDER]
- [COMICAL MUSIC PLAYING]
- I'd rather die now...
- Go back to Betchay!
- ...than watch my husband die!
- Please help us!
- [CONTINUES WAILING]
- [SALVADOR] Wait, wait!
- I can't breathe!
- Come here!
- Move over there!
[MAMENG, BETCHAY WAILING]
Bring her next to Mameng!
Help her walk!
Ma'am, I'm not your husband!
I'm not your husband!
Wait, ma'am! Let go!
- Please help my husband!
- My brother!
- My poor brother!
- Please have mercy on us!
- Did you get that?
- [OLI] Yes, I got it all.
Good take! That's enough.
[ENGINE REVVS]
[ARNEL] Salvador.
I'm telling you,
make sure your report
has heart and feelings.
To make the people
more interested!
It's lacking!
- Your report is lacking.
- You want me to overdo it?
I feel like I'm deceiving
the people.
What do you mean
by deceiving?!
It's true that the police
were the ones who shot
her husband.
All we're doing is adding
more life to the interview!
Stand there.
Stand right there.
- Right here?
- Take a shot of him here.
So people can see
how poor they are!
- Alright!
- This angle right there.
Right there!
[OLI] Two... thee... take!
After speaking with the lady,
one question still arises.
One. How long will the law
protectors be held accountable?
Second.
Instead of peace,
this operation left behind fear.
Third. Instead of protection,
they all felt anxiety.
The residents who have
already lost their homes
may also risk losing
their loved ones.
Right?
Thank you.
Be more aggressive!
Let out your anger
towards the police!
Don't be like that.
Be more aggressive!
Like picking a fight?
That's not who I am.
We need to show
how angry we are!
Find a way to do that, Salvador.
Let's find a way to show that
to the viewers!
You can't be like that!
- Make that happen.
- [OLI] Salvador, let's go.
- Cheers, sir!
- [OLI] Hey.
[OLI] Salvador!
- Is that clean?
- [MAN] Of course, it is!
Just take a shot.
Here you go.
You really are a scene-stealer.
Hey!
I was just...
I was wondering,
what if we really lose Rudy?
He's my brother, of course,
I'd react that way!
[SIGHS]
But, what do you think, huh?
Do you think
they'll really help us
get a lawyer
so we can file
against the police?
You want to file
a case against them?
Of course, I do!
Shouldn't we seek justice
for what they've done to Rudy?
Whoever did it should
be held accountable!
That would be a hassle.
I'm sure they'll cover for
their fellow police officers.
It will just lead to nowhere!
I thought you loved Rudy!
Why don't you want
to seek justice for him?!
I love your brother so much!
I also want the person
who shot him arrested!
But if we file a case
against the police,
it's just like picking up a rock
and smashing it against
our own heads.
[CROWD CHEERING]
[ARNEL] That's enough.
Let's get back to work!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[ARNEL] That's enough.
Let's get back to work!
There you go, sir!
- [OLI] Are you okay?
- [ARNEL] Are you okay?
- Yes!
- Alright, let's go!
Okay, okay.
[OLI] Please, step aside.
- [SALVADOR] Let me speak.
- Do a good job.
Three, two, one... action!
After interviewing
the woman whose husband
is currently in critical
condition at the hospital,
following a demolition
that was supposed to be peaceful
led by the police.
A huge question now looms
over the family.
Who shot him? Who?
And why did that have
to happen?
We won't stop covering
this story
until all those responsible
are held accountable!
You can count on that.
Salvador
"The Vindicator" Manalo.
Manila Telebalita.
That's it! Great!
- Hey!
- Hey.
[ARNEL] That's good,
that's great.
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATION]
[ISOBEL] Ricardo...
[ISOBEL SIGHS]
How's Manny?
The people at Ginintuang Lupa
filed a TRO.
Looks like they found
a lawyer.
[ISOBEL EXHALES]
Of course, they're going
to fight for that.
That's the only thing
they have left.
But it's impressive
that they found an ally.
Yeah, Isobel,
but you already know it.
The law can be bent
so long as you have money.
It's just a waste of their time
and resources.
Ricardo, is--
Is this worth it?
What?
Everything.
[TWINKLE] There--
Uh, ma'am!
Ricardo. Isobel.
I have some bad news.
[ISOBEL] Bad news?
What is it?
The Japanese investors
backed out of your development!
- My god!
- No, that can't happen.
I laid out my vision
for Ginintuang Lupa to them.
And they liked it!
[ISOBEL] Is this because
of what the people
at Ginintuang Lupa did?
Those rude bastards?
[PINKY] They heard
about the demolition,
and how a lot of people
got hurt!
They don't want to be a part
of this mess!
Wait. I'll talk to them.
No, I'll make them commit
to the project.
I'll bring them back.
They said
their decision's final.
They don't want us
to contact them again!
[ISOBEL] Ah, Ricardo...
Why don't we just sell
Ginintuang Lupa?
Doesn't matter if we lose money,
or earn little.
Let's just get rid
of this problem!
Isobel, it's not that easy
to sell land.
Pinky was trying for how long.
She's wanted to get rid of it
for a long time now!
But no one wanted it!
I'm the only one
who came forward
because, as I said,
we have influence.
I mean, I'll solve any problem
the development will face.
But, come on!
I didn't expect this
to be the reaction
of the people
at Ginintuang Lupa.
It's very difficult to resell
that property.
Why don't we look
for investors?
Let's focus on that instead!
Pinky, what investors are
you talking about?
The peso's down!
The government's already
in turmoil.
What investors can we get
at this time?!
I will try to find a way.
I'll try to talk
to some people.
Isobel, the development
of Ginintuang Lupa will happen.
Remember, I was raised
not to fail.
And I don't intend to start now.
[DOOR OPENS]
[EXHALES SOFTLY]
- [SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING]
- [DOORS OPEN]
Doc, how's Papa doing?
The patient's condition
is critical.
He needs surgery right away.
If we don't do it soon,
his lungs could collapse,
oxygen won't reach his brain,
and it could cost him his life.
Don't worry, Doc.
I'll find a way right now
to get my father
into surgery immediately.
Understood.
- [SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [HEART MONITOR BEEPING]
Pa, please hold on tight.
I'm doing everything I can
so you'll get better soon.
When I come back, I promise...
...I'll bring the money we need.
I won't let anything
happen to you, Pa.
I'll do whatever it takes
to see you wake up again.
Even if I have to risk
my very own life...
I won't let anything bad
befall you, Pa.
[SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
[HEART MONITOR BEEPING]
Crowds are everywhere,
it's Chinese New Year.
Gabo sure gives us
rough assignments, huh?
We're supposed to track down
someone we've never even met.
Mariano and I worked so hard
to build all of this up.
So I want you
to prioritize the business.
Every player's
got their own plan...
(In Cantonese) Wishing you
a happy, prosperous New Year!
What a smell! Who just farted?!
Daboy,
give us a heads-up next time!
- That wasn't me, come on!
- It's all over my clothes too!
Who will strike first?
Get inside and run
surveillance on the place.
Is your boss here?
Ma'am, do you really think
we can pull this off?
This case we're handling
is way too heavy.
- That won't be an issue.
- We'll follow Mr. Chan,
he'll lead us straight
to Tiger.